now I'd like to show you a large
collection and the
impact that indexes can have on
performance so I've loaded up
ten million documents into a collection
and I'm gonna show you that in the Mongo
shell
its in the school database in the
student collection
and i'm looking a single document in the
collection which is a great way to get
an understanding
on what they look like assuming its
regular and it is in this case
you can see each document has 290
and a buncha scores for the student is a
force s mental exam a quiz and homework
homework
this is the grades they got in this
particular class
and so their $10 million documents so
is one million students have each taken
ten classes now there's absolutely
no indexes on this collection so let's
see how long it would take
to do occur in this collection and try
to find
all the information for student ID let's
say five
which should be very early in their
collection to just inserted
it was probably inserted in order on the
desk
and it I'm running the MFB 1/ stored
engine in this case all right let's do
that
all right that took a few seconds to
return those 10 documents
and this is a fast computer this is a4
gigahertz core i7 computer with 32
gigabytes of memory
and a fusion drive has a combination SSD
and speed is gone so that a long time
that a lot of cycles
for a computer this fast so the question
is
how Queen make it faster before do that
I want to show you a couple things
first is that there is an explain
command that we're going over in a
little lesson
that will show you the secret that what
the database is doing
when execute a query and I work if you
will for shadowing this command
it runs on top of a collection so DB
that students dans the collection
explain is the command
and then the chain what you wanna do in
this case you want to find you can also
chain update or delete and
it's going to tell you what index is it
would have used to
satisfy this great now in this case
there are any index is it can use
and it's going to scan all ten million
document it should tell us that
so we look to the output explain will go
through it more detail later lesson
the interesting part is right here in
the winning plan section where you can
see it says
it's doing art collection scam it's
looking at
all the documents and that's that's
going to be pretty slow
now if we actually to find one
versus the find then it'll be faster
and the reason it'll be faster is that
wanted find a single document they can
quit looking
and so since the documents are probably
in 290 or approximately right now
that can be fairly fast you can see that
was fast
didn't take very long for it to return a
single document for this 295 but we want
general find to work well
so 11 an index how do we do that let's
at the annex
DB dot students dot create index
and there is a scam case inside the
shell lo que sea
upper case I and now we're going to
present the document to create an axe
that describes the index and this case
we're saying we want it to be indexed on
student ID ascending
we'll talk all the more about what that
means later but we're gonna hit return
this can take a while so I'm gonna time
this off-camera
so I can tell you how long it took on
this superfast computer
here we go okay it took about twenty
three seconds on this computer to create
this index
and that's important to note because
even a really fast computer
creating index takes a while because we
have to scan the entire collection
create new data structures and write
them all to desk
right now that we have index this search
on
finding all the students with 295 should
be nice and fast
let's see if this who night in fast
and it was and everyone explain command
we're gonna see that it now using index
slut see that alright I ran the explain
command once again
and you can see now it says the winning
plan for this type of query
is the use the index name student
underscored the one not fantastic
and one little other secret able explain
that if re give a true and there's two
ways to give arguments to explain this
is actually the older one
then it'll actually run the query as
well which means you can tell us how
many
document actually
looked at in the execution stages the
query and you can see
that number of documents examined was
exactly
10 net pretty cool want to use the index
only had actually look at 10 documents
Wow at fantastic alright now you can
also add a compound index
to this collection and we want to add a
compound index
we would do it as such we would give a
second key
and then ascending or descending so for
instance this is the command you'd give
to create an index on student ID comma
class ID
with us tonight the part was ascending
and the class any part was descending
and this will affect the grease we just
did but they will affect
things like sorting where if the index
is aren't in the right order and
depending on how specify the sort
you may not be able to use the index
okay
so now it is time for requests
please read the manga show command to
add in next to a collection name
students having the index key
be class commerce student underscore
name and neither these will be in the
minus one direction
type your answer right here