okay knowing how to create indexes on a
collection how would you discover what
indexes are already on the collection
well we can do that with the get indexes
command
so I'm gonna start them on a shell again
in once again I'm any use the
school database and then I'm going to
call
DB dot students got get indexes
students the name the collection and as
you remember the last lesson we just
added an index to it
first to ninety recall getting Nexus if
we do that we get back
this result which is a document actually
to the rave to documents
and the first one tell you that there is
an
index underscore I D now this index
exist in all collections and you can't
delete there's also an index on student
underscored a
and that index we just created and we
wanted to you
get rid of that index we would call DB
dot Stevens dot drop in X and
provide this exact same signature as we
created
so here are calling drop in tax and
we're giving the same signature students
cried econ one that we gave we created
the index
if we do that we should be able to drop
and there you go
I'm indexes was too and now it's one and
if we get index is again will see that
in fact
there is only one index perfect alright
one last point I want to make is that
this call get indexes
is a call that you use in Mongo DB 3.0
and will work on both wired tiger and
I'm at b1
and an earlier version to the database
you could
look at a special collection system the
indexes
to see you indexes existed that does not
work
in wire tiger and so that preferred way
to figure out what next on a collection
is to do this to call DB that students
that it can indexes and again
is a change in Mongo DB 3.0