now wanna talk to you about how you can
use dot notation
to reach deep into a document and and
Nexus something that in a sub document
have the main document and also doing
this with things that are race
so combining multi key with dot notation
it's a pretty cool feature among many be
a little tricky to explain how it works
and Mac work exactly as you expect so
let me show you some examples
alright I'm back in the Mongo shell now
and I'm gonna look at this
students collection once again to DB
that students not find one
this is the same collection we look at
my previous lesson and it has
these documents that have structure
where the student ID and then into
scores are a
and this was a ray has a bunch of
documents as elements in the array
were each document has type examine a
score
and is also a class ID so let's say we
wanted to index
on this score itself we can do that the
call would be as follows:
DB that students that create index
scores that score
is one that's how we would do it that
would create an index
they were index this array and the sub
par this document and I did this
off-camera the took
about 15-20 minutes to create the syntax
because his ten million documents this
for element in this array
and it took a long time so you can see
where indexes
ahranat on the collection will do that
right now and
if you call the doc indexes you can see
there are now two indexes on the
collection
one is an underscore I D and the other
one on scores that score
which is a multi key index so what can
you do with that
well first of all you could search for
records where
any score was above a certain value so
it looks back worry looks like
this will find everything where scores
that score
is greater than 99% and actually reached
an understanding with the query
optimizer does with it
that actually seeing the results some
I'm using explain
to return that information let's do that
ever did that query you can see that
and gonna do an index can says right
here winning plan included
the scores that score index in the
forward direction that look for things
were scores that scores between 99.0
infinity
and that's how it to retrieve this
information everyone to see that
information we can just remove the
explain
part of this and then with documents
back
where there is a will least one score
above 99 but pretty printed we can see
that more clearly
you can see that in this case it was the
homework that was above
99 so what if we want to find people
that had an exam score that was above 99
how would we do that now I'm gonna show
you the query
and then I'll show you a crude I used
before I looked into it more carefully
turned out to be wrong I think it's
interesting example because it easy to
get confused about this
so the crew that would search for all
the students where an exam scores but 99
looks like this and it uses this LM at
operators were gonna go through this
very carefully
it's actually being run explain right
now but let let's look at
so we're trying to inspect the scores
array
inside document and then wanna find a
document
which has an element of the array that
is a
type exam and a score greater than 99.8
and to do that we use this operator
called LM match
lol match does and you can look it up in
documentation
is it matches documents that contain an
array field
with at least one element that matters
all the specified group criteria
so in other words there might be more
than one element among the more than one
examine this array that match this
criteria
but we're going to make sure that we
match at least one with all this
criteria so it's looking for
element at the type exam and score
greater than
99.8 and if we do that let's first
just get the results we can confirm that
works to my pretty print the result we
see that we get
something that has an exam score about
99.8
works perfectly well very nice wonder
how many records there are just a
curiosity that would satisfy these
criteria
and the answer is that there are 20,000
student that satisfy these criteria of
having exam score
greater than 99.8 in a somewhat random
data set
up ten I and documents alright what are
the explain %uh public like this cuz
thats
that sort of interesting question to me
alright let's run this would explain now
to see what the crew optimizer
is gonna do to satisfy this query and do
that
I need to
remove discount the and I just need to
do
and explain tell that I wanna see what
it would do with this find command
gonna run that and it's pretty
interesting we're gonna go over explain
in more detail
but you can see is a worldwide
information here
but the winning plan it's kinda easy to
read this from the
bottom to the top because actually you
can't quite tell but
this is the first thing it runs I
believe it says that first
it runs a query on scores that score
being 99.8 to infinity okay that makes
perfect sense
because thats what the index is so we
can't do any better than to look at the
scores that score
key and after that it runs the output at
that this is an index can
into the next stage where it does and
find all the doctor disaster that
criteria which is probably
Cenex or 45 X number documents that we
have an exam that score
and then it runs the LM match and as you
know what I wanna find something with a
score
that's greater than 99.8 type that exam
causes a fetch I don't believe in
anything special I can do here
I think it actually generates to every
single document
and inspect them and we can confirm that
by running it with value true and let
execute the query tsunami documentary
examines
and the answer is that examined
to right here regularly explain output
too hard to read on the screen
but again we have the winning plan for
missions exactly the same as before
but now we have furnish information call
execution stats
and it is kinda go through here and look
at what's interesting
and then we can see that it returned
twenty thousand documents
okay it makes sense but it examined
eighty thousand documents wow okay and
you know that number is it's probably
the number of documents
they have score about 99.8 so let's just
confirm that's true
score greater than 99.8 give me a
counter those
and there are 80,000 54
documents they have score greater than
99.8 an
and it examined every single one of them
for this query see we can find this
information
to the execution stats for the query and
you can see it examined 80,000
54 documents to return 20,000 107 a
document
that missus with mommy went to this
query is that use the index it had
which was on scores not score and then
after that
it is essential to scan everything that
resulted to do the LM at sparred
alright now what mistakes I make my was
saying this lesson up and thinking about
it
turn out to be wrong and the answer is I
try to use this query
and work with her to carefully but
Research UK to confuse me
all right here the curry I tried to use
to get the answer every student had the
exam
about 99.8 I tried to use the and
operator
and said you know what I wanna find
fangs
where scores that type is examined
scores that score is greater than 99.8
and when I did that you know what I
found I found document that look like
this
I found documents where there is a score
greater than 99.8
but it wasn't for the exam really
interesting ha so actually
if you use this and operator there's no
guarantee that when it find a doctor
that satisfies
this criteria without the L A match part
let it satisfies
this criteria in the same sub-par might
be different part
and this really comes out when you look
at the explain upper actually
explain output help you understand the
way
the database interpreted this query in
20 cities explain up it
you like oh yeah of course makes perfect
sense so
explain output said here's what we're
gonna do
here's a winning plan okay it said in
the first stage
in this lowest level stage I wanna find
everything with scores that score above
99.8
and pass that up to the next stage and
the next age
should look for things that scores that
I people exam ho dear that's not right
because basically it's returning all
these documents during a huge number of
documents from the stage at 12 we know
how many the 80,000
students have 99.8 and above so first
does this query find all the students
with us
with any score above 99.8 their past
that this next agent says
now buy me all the documents where
scores that type
is equal to exam and that's not going to
work
because that is gonna give you things
where the score was not for the actual
exam
now compare that output to watch out we
got
for the correct query but the ally
matsch we use the correct query for this
look at the output very different in
that case the first aid to the query
did the exact same thing at look for
things with scores that score but 99.8
but in the second stage lenders look for
them to type exam
we looked for an element match where
both conditions were true
with the score was again 99.8 reaffirmed
that this was true for the document and
that the type was exam her right
headline inflation I hope that helps
better explain
no pun intended how that works okay time
for quitters
spose have a collection call people in
the database earth
and documents in the following form: you
can see the documents here
what would be the command in the manga
shell to create an index
on company descending please type your
answer right down here