welcome to week for congratulations on
making at this point
this week we're gonna talk about
performance the performance of computer
systems driven by a variety of factors
including the performance of the
underlying hardware CPU the desk in the
memory
once you've chosen hardware
configuration it's gonna be your
algorithm that the term performance and
for database backup application
it can be the our rhythms they're used
to satisfy your queries
there are two ways you can impact the
latency and throughput
database queries one is at indexes to
collections
and two is to distribute the load across
multiple servers
using shorting this week we're gonna
talk about performance
but to make matter to look more
interesting in manga to be three point
I'll we introduce portable storage
engines
storage engine is the software the
controls how the data is stored
on desk also to talk about hugs twice
the storage engine impact performance
now performance is normally
the domain a database administrators but
good developers
understand performance and write their
applications with performance in mind
and the bug performed at problems with
their applications
let's get started