let's talk about creating indexes on
arrays we call these indexes
multi key indexes so imagine you have a
collection
document that look similar to this: this
document has named Andrew
tags: photography hiking in golf some of
my passions
color red I don't know why I just picked
it and then
location is also an array New York Comic
California
you can create and index on tax
and if you do that they were among the
DB indexes
the collection and if the stock already
in there
then it would create an index point for
photography hiking in Gulf
you can also create an index on if you
wanted
tags: comma color and in that case
Mon BB would create for instance for
this document
index points for photography red
hiking reading girlfriend now mode the
key indexes
become all the key indexes with the
database realizes that their is a
document
with an array as one of the keys up the
index
and there are restrictions on use some
of the key indexes
in particular you can't have two items
at a compound in texas is a compound
index
where both them are a race so for
instance
this index would not be legal tags:
comma location if there was already a
document in the collection
where both tags: and location were a
race
and when Mama you tell you that can't
index parallel rays
and the reason is there's an explosion
in export the created because has to
grade index point for the cartesian
product on the item's
in the race and it doesn't permit that
nothing to remember
is that when you first create an index
it there's nothing nothing in the
collection
Mongo DB doesn't know that there maybe
an array for instance in tags in the
future and so on index only becomes more
ticket when the first document it
added has as its value for the keys
an array so that sounds kinda
complicated let's go through a concrete
Lee and look inside the shell
to get a better understanding of how
this works alright
so let's start the Mongo shell buffoon
collection which is empty
recruit a simple document where A's won
and B is to okay and if we do that
get certain you can see it in there no
problem now he wanted to create an index
on a comedy we could do that by typing
DB dot
food ot create index a
ascending be sending there was one in it
now there are two
and if we use our friendly explain
command that we're getting to know
better and better
foo collection I'll explain and then to
a find
where it's a a is one perfectly
reasonable
query how A's 1b is one will say we can
look here and we can see that
in the query planner stage at this
explain output
it tells about the winning plan and the
winning plan
was to use index can on the index
a underscore 1b underscore one and
that's the name for the a comer be index
if we do get indexes we'd see that and
it tells us
that it is not morteki index okay
fair enough well that makes sense i mean
is not much in this thing we saw that
all there is is the single document and
it doesn't have an already the part
but now let's insert something else into
here let's answer document
where a is three and be
is a reggae 3 come five common 7 now
if we did that now at this point
if we run the exact same career and
before and we do a find
a couple one becoming one and we're at
the explain command
then way up we get sick well
once again it tells us that using this
index
a comer be a and a score 1 p.m. square
one index
but this time it says multi key true and
every course issue this command without
the explain
it would find exactly no document
because there are no documents
but as far as criteria not see what was
in the collections we can get a better
query
we have a come a three and become a five
let's look for
documents that have a comma three and
become a five that'll be in there
a comer 3 become a five now for did that
then we get the one document right there
and again if we look at it we
explain will see that query also
produces same as all telling us that
using the multi key index the index has
been
ritmo de ke and again if you do get an
excellent collection
you'll see that the index is called and
a score one being square one
what we saw inside explain up let's say
we did something else let's say that we
actually now
inserted something in this collection
where both
a NBA worries like for instance 345
and B is 789
if we insert something into the
collection or both
anbe RA's stock at work
to say I'm sorry I can't put anything
into this
index we're both A&B are both a race
alright so this makes sense I mean we
have this collection
and we can see what's in it we can see
that we have
two different documents in the second
one B is a list or array in
NA is not what if we wanted to insert
something
where a was a last NB was
a scaler would that be okay and the
answer is
yes biggest this is not a multi key
index in a way that says 0 be always has
to be an array
its MOT key index and allows any
combination so for instance
a can be in Arabi can be a scale or or
be can be an array in a can be a scale
and they're both legal
is that you can anyone document we're
both anbe
in this compound index are both a race I
hope that's clear
and the other thing is that once an
accident upgraded to multi key
if you dropped all documents are this
collection it would still say it was not
a key we didn't explain
on the collection so the key takeaways
here is that
you can at indexes honourees and
you can create copper indexes that
include a raise but when you have an
index that is more tricky and where at
least one document has
value being an array you can have
multiple values have a compaq index both
be an array
that's not legal alright time for quiz
multi key indexes
suppose we have a collection through has
index created as follows:
who created next a one be one just seem
very familiar to you
if you watch the lesson
which have these following inserts our
ballot this collection
check all that apply