this week is mostly about indexing and
at the very end the week we're gonna
talk about charting
which is distributing database queries
across multiple servers
but before we do that we need to
introduce you to the idea of what a
storage engine is
inside the database because this was a
big year from on BB
new manga to be 3.0 is that we offer
pluggable storage engines now what is a
storage engine
a storage engine is the interface
between
the persistent storage which will call
the desks but might be solved a desk
and the database itself Mongo DB and
this is the Mongo DB server
so mama DB server talks to the desk the
persistent storage
through a storage engine so this
that the storage engine right there and
you the program are you gonna be writing
say a pipe bomb program and CV writing
in Python
and it'll be using the pie Mongo
driver which talked to the database
server
using the wire protocol and when it
wants to
create data re data update and delete
data
ill talk to the storage engine which
will then talk to the desk
and all the different structures the
whole the document that old indexes in
the meta data involving the documents
are all written to the persistent
storage by this
storage engine now it may be the case
that the storage engine itself decides
to use
memory to optimize the process so in
other words
disc is really slow so since the idea
databases to store stuff persistently
what happens is the storage engine has
control of memory on your computer
and they can decide what to put in
memory
and what they got a memory and what to
persist a desk in when
to database server itself defers the
handling of the memory on the server
as well as disc itself to storage engine
now
we offer a pluggable storage engine
architecture
where you can use more than one the idea
here is that let's say you had a car and
you wanted to have
different engines you could put the
engine in the car and that it would
probably change the cars
performance characteristics for instance
it might
accelerate faster or might get better or
worse gas mileage
because the type engine you put into
your car
and so early depending on the type
engine that you put into manga DB
you're going to get different
performance characteristics and that's
why it's important that we have some
basic understanding this
before we move on this week there are
two main storage engine the chipmunk DB
that we support
and one of them is called and map and
the other one is called wired Tiger
and that is the default it's what you
get if you don't given the options to
manga de when you start at the command
line
and evaporated with have this work has
been the storage engine for quite a
while
wire Tiger came into acquisition 2014
Mongo DB acquired the White Paper
Company is the same
team that built Berkeley DB and also a
lot of them were at the company sleepy
cat
if you know your computer history
alright
so now I have some basic understanding
about a storied engineers so what is the
store and engine not
what are some other things the storage
engine doesn't handle well if you have a
bunch of Mongo DB servers all running in
a cluster
the storage engine doesn't affect the
communication between Nos
different Mongo DB servers and the
Georgian doesn't affect
the API that database presents to the
programmer
for example its the same pretty much
where they're not use a map or white
tiger
but there are going to be some
differences in performance and that's
why we're going to Scotts
alright now it's time for Chris storage
engine directly determines which of the
following
check all that apply the data file
format architecture a cluster
the wire protocol for the drivers and
the format the indexes
I didn't directly talk about some of
these so you might have to guess based
on what I said