okay let's talk about index is now and
their impact on database performance
now this is a imagined collection right
here
a bunch of documents and the documents
might have the form shown
right here this is a collection and
these documents might be
on desk and essentially arbitrary order
and whether you're talking about a map
v1 or wired Tiger
might be no particular order to the
document on desk no
it is no index and you wanted to find
all the documents where let's say
name was Joey you would need to scan
every document in the collection and
there could be millions of those
and this collections can or a table
scans called the relational world is
just
death to performance it's probably the
single greatest factor on whether or not
you cruise and perform well
more important than speed the CPU more
important than how much memory you have
is whether or not you can use some sort
of index to avoid having to look at the
entire
collection to how the index work what
what is an index one indexes ordered set
up things
so imagine that we just had a simple
index on let's say the name interpreter
symbol next to name
you can think a bit as an ordered list
of things
for instance Andrew might be on the left
to the alphabetically early
and Zoe might be on the right in the
middle might be
barey and Charlie Center NDTV's
index points has a pointer to a physical
record so it's gonna have some sorta
pointer to a location on a desk or maybe
underscore ID
for the document you can find the record
so
very record might be right here Charlie
record might be right there
sorry record might be right there the
nice thing about having something it's
ordered is it's very fast
to search it because it was actually a
linear
a list like this in its it's not in a
typical database but it was linear like
this
then you could search using a binary
search and
it would take you log to you are the
number of items in this list
in real databases and Mongo DB
the actual with this index structures
called a b-tree and
looking or to be treason look beyond the
scope of this course but if you just go
on Google and search for be true you get
a great Wikipedia page explains it
pretty well do you wanna put these
indexes
on the item's that you believe you're
going to be clearing on
that's gonna make wearying much faster
but sometimes we don't just want to
query
on let's say name we also want to query
on
name and maybe her collar so
how that work well an exxon name in hair
color will be represented
as follows: the right name como hair
color
and that ordered and if you did that
then all the
index entries would be ordered by
name.com hair color
so for instance there might be an index
entry for
Andrew comma Blanc
and that's going to be a single in next
entry tell represent
by making a green like this and then
there might be another index entry
for Andrew comma red
and again that's just one next entry
right here
to have another next entry here and
Andrew bond my
refer to this document here into redneck
for
this document here and then you might
have 14
barey brown hair
and then that's going to be right here
maybe that points
over here and another 14 dairy
red which might be a document that is
over there and then the far corner here
let's say another index entry 40 we and
then
right there at and maybe that document
is for more
there these documents which show you
where they are there in the order I love
name come here /color
so you can kinda see that if you want to
find let's say all the
berries with a certain color hair did
you do it
pretty easily because you go again do a
binary search the structure
and then do it again to this party
structure to find that's a very red hair
you also do range queries so you could
say find me all the berries with
hair that's greater than or equal to
brown in less than or equal to read
that would also work but if on the other
hand he specified just a hair color
economy stuck right because if
I said just fire me all the ball hair
color red their sorrow
all over the place right and not order
in a particular way
in this larger structures I can't use a
binary search to find them
so as a result whenever I'm using index
I need to use a left most said things
so if the index were let's extended
and included the date of birth then
I could search on just the name that
would work
in this index that I could do and I saw
search rocket surgeon the name in the
hair color
orchestra to name the hair color the
birth but I can come in we just gave
birth
or just the hair color because then I
had no way of searching this
this index so let me review what I just
said if you have an index indexes are
going to be described
this way when we talk about them AB and
C
then you can search on a you can search
a AB
you consider a BC see alone
no see Calabi no and if you search
daresay a comer si
then it to a partial yes because it
would use the index for the a portion
and that the search to all them see
portion
the other point I want to make is that
indexing is not free
because whenever you change something in
a document
which affects the index you're gonna
have to up to 10x you're gonna have to
write on memory eventually on desk
many indexes are presented the way I did
linearly their representatives be tree
that maintain these be trees takes time
so as a result if you have a collection
and you have indexes on their collection
and the right affect items that were
indexed the rights will be slower
that there was no index that's right
indexing actually slows down your rights
but your reads will be much faster
now if you were just writing and you
never want to ever ever find a document
you when I wanna have an index
because then you can insert the document
will be inserted anywhere on the desk
it doesn't matter where and there be no
index to maintain
and in fact wanna strategies when
inserting a very large
about data into database is to have no
indexes on the actual collection at all
to insert all the data and then after
all that is inserted
then add in Texas and then build the
index is that way you don't have
to incur maintain the index is why you
add data incrementally
the fact that writer slower in the fact
that takes time
updated index in every single right that
affects
anything index is one the reasons why
you don't just wanna have an index
on every single key in a collection
because we had Indexed everything ok in
the collection
then you're gonna slow down your rights
more and you really is a lot more disk
space to to maintain
those index as we point out that we had
ten million items
in a collection and there's no indexing
you search on something anything
you look at 10:09 documents and that's
pretty expensive
and get a look at ten million documents
are 100 million documents and Amanda
member you have is
much smaller than the amount of desk or
space that the doctors are present on
desk
then you're going to wind up swapping
all those documents to memory in
creating a tremendous amount of disk i/o
which is going to pretty slow and these
were indexing is so absolutely critical
to performance alright now it is time
for Chris
which optimization will typically have
the greatest impact on the performance
database to consider four choices here
adding memory so that the working set
but a memory
adding a faster drives the operations
ahead this will happen more quickly
replacing your CPU with the faster one
say twice as fast
or adding appropriate next time art
collections that only a small percent in
the queries
in DC and the collection check the right
answer