let's talk about the m map storage
engine we call em at b1
the original stored engine Mongo DB and
it uses the
m ap system call under the covers in
order to implement
storage management let's look at what
them out to them call
looks like it's right here if you do on
any UNIX machine if you man and map
you'll see their talks about allocating
memory or mapping files are devices into
memory
cause the pages starting in addressing
continuing for most left by three maps
in the object described by the fountain
scripture
an offset so what does that mean that
practically mean
well mommy be the place to put documents
and put a document inside files
and to do that initially allocates let's
say a large file a TLK two hundred
gigabyte file on disk
21 it with a hundred about file on desk
right here
and this this may or may not be
physically contiguous on the actual disc
is there some I rhythms that
occur beneath that layer that control
the actual allocation of space and a
desk
but from our standpoint 200 by
continuous file if mommy because the AM
map system call
it can map this file 100 about file into
100 gigabytes a virtual memory
now to do that of course we need to be
on a 64 bit computer
because you can never get a hundred
gigabytes virtual memory space on 32-bit
computer you'd be limited to two or four
gigabytes
and these are all paid sized so pages on
operators demory therefore care 16k
large show there's a lot of them they're
not showing here
and they are pretty stems gonna decide
what can fit in memory
so if the actual physical memory in the
boxes that say 32 gigabytes
then if I go to access one of the pages
in this memory space
maybe not be a memory at any given time
they are prints from the sides
which these pages are going to be a
memory other to the green ones are in
memory
and so when you go to read a document if
it hits a page that
in memory then you get it and even if
the page that's not memory that say this
page
then the operating system has two bring
it from desk
this is on this care as the ring at
front desk into memory before:
you can access it and that the basics
love where the a map storage engine
works
now their map storage engine offers
collection level concurrency
or we sometimes call collection level
locking
each collection inside Mon BB his own
file
if you look in Davis last TB so that
means that if you have two different
operations going on at the same time
and they are in the same collection was
gonna have to wait for the other one if
they're right
because it's a multiple readers single
writer locked that text
so only one right can happen at a time
to a particular collection
but if they're different collections and
it could happen simultaneously
in addition the way the storied engine
works a map v1
we allow in place updates our data to
the document is sitting here in this a
paid right here
and you an update to it then we'll try
to update it right in place
and if we can update it they will do is
well market as a whole
and then we'll move it somewhere else
where there is more space or moved over
here or something
and the mop head over there you were to
make it more likely that we can update a
doctor in place without having
to move it we use power of two sizes
when we allocate the initial storage for
document that means that if you try to
create a free by document unit 4 buy it
if you try to clean
a seven by documenting a bytes and
nineteen bite document you're gonna get
32 bytes and this way it's more likely
that you can grow the document orbit
and that space that opens up that we can
reuse it more easily
so that the M maps toward engine and
you'll notice that since the operating
system is what makes a decision about
what is in memory
purses what is in desk we can't really
do much in terms of controlling that
Japanese firms pretty smart about
managing memory so
it's usually not about algorithm but
database doesn't get too
the side or contributed to pinyin about
what wind up
in physical memory verses what went up
on desk and
if you're curious about the waiver to
memory works in general just you go over
to memory and storage systems and
it's the same algorithms that are used
to manage memory inside
the opposite them for all programs okay
now it's time for quiz
which the following statements about the
MFB 1/ storage engine are true
check all that apply the first the IM
app offers doctor unlocking
the second a.m. app automatically
allocates power to size documents a new
documents are inserted
the third a map it doesn't happen the a
map system called naps files into memory
and the final one is that mom would be
mad to the memories by each map file
deciding which parts what the desk
so Tech 21 you think are correct