All right.
Now you know about the
MMAP storage engine.
Let's talk about the Wired
Tiger storage engine.
This storage is not turned on
by default inside MongoDB in 3.0
but it offers some
interesting features,
and for a lot of
workloads, it is faster.
The first is that it offers
document level concurrency.
Now, we don't call it document
level locking because it's
actually a lock free
implementation which
has an optimistic concurrency
model where the storage
engine assumes that two
writes are not going
to be to the same
document, and if they are
to the same document,
then one of those writes
is unwound and has to
try again, and it's
invisible to the
actual application.
But we do get this
document level concurrency
versus collection level
concurrency in the MMAP storage
engine, and that's a huge win.
The second is that this storage
engine offers compression,
both of the documents
themselves, of the data,
and of the indexes.
And it's beyond the
scope of this course
to go over exactly how all this
works, but just very broadly,
the Wired Tiger storage engine.
We talked before about
having a 100 gigabyte file,
and if you had a 100 gigabyte
file on disk using Wired Tiger,
Wired Tiger itself
manages the memory that
is used to access that file.
So the file is
brought in in pages,
and the pages can
be of varying sizes,
and Wired Tiger
decides which blocks
it's going to keep
in memory and which
blocks to send back to disk.
So it's because Wired Tiger
is managing its own storage
that Wired Tiger can,
for instance, compress.
You don't want to keep
it compressed in memory
because when you have
read access to a document,
if they hit memory and
they hit your cache of data
that's in memory, you don't
want to have to decompress it.
And with Wired Tiger,
you don't have to
because it's kept in
the clear in memory,
but before they write out the
disk, they can compress it,
and that saves a
tremendous amount of space
for certain types of data.
And if you think about
MongoDB, the keys
are often repeated in
every single document,
so there's a lot of
opportunities for compression.
Wired Tiger is also an
append only storage engine.
There are no in place updates.
That means that if you update
a document in Wired Tiger, what
they're going to
do is they're going
to mark that the document
is no longer used
and they're going to
allocate new space somewhere
else on disk and they're
going to write it there.
And eventually, they reclaim the
space that is no longer used.
This can result in writing
a lot of data sometimes.
If you have very large documents
and you only update one item,
Wired Tiger is going to have
to write that entire document
again, but it's this
append only nature
of the way they
store the data that
allows it to run without
locks at the document level
and gives them the
document level concurrency.
So overall, it's often faster.
If you want to start the
database with the Wired Tiger
storage engine,
you can do it using
the flag -storageEngine and
then after that, wired tiger.
My handwriting's
kind of poor, so I'm
going to show you on the
screen what this looks like.
So the first thing
you want to do
is kill your existing
mongod process,
and then you can create a new
directory, for instance, called
WT for Wired Tiger, and
then you could start Mongo
by telling it to use that
directory, dbpath Wired Tiger.
That tells it to use this
Wired Tiger directory.
I'll do .WT, although I
don't think I need that.
Actually, I don't
think I need that.
dbpath WT, put the
files in that directory,
and then I would need to give
it the storageEngine flag
and then say Wired Tiger.
So mongod -dbpath.
Normally, it defaults into
/data/db if you don't give it
any arguments, but we need a
new directory because the Wired
Tiger storage engine cannot open
the files created by MMAP V1.
So if you have been running
MongoDB on your computer,
on your desktop, for
example, and you kill it,
and you try to start up using
storage engine Wired Tiger,
it won't work because it
can't read those files.
So if we hit Return, you can
see that Wired Tiger is starting
and it's listening on
27017, and that if we just
clear the screen and
connect using Mongo,
then we can do
db.foo.insert name andrew.
And now we've written something
into a Wired Tiger based
storage engine inside MongoDB.
And if I want to know that it
is a Wired Tiger based storage
engine, I'm in the
test database right
now and the foo collection.
If you call
db.foo.stats, you can
see it tells you a bunch
of things about the stats,
about this collection, including
its size, which is small,
and that it has this Wired Tiger
key that tells you that it's
a Wired Tiger collection.
So that's it.
Now it's time for a quiz.
Which of the following are
features of the Wired Tiger
storage engine?
Check all that apply.
In place update of documents,
power of two document padding,
document level concurrency,
compression, and turbocharged.
Which of these are true?